Guide to the G. William Skinner papers, 1948-1988, 1951-1958 (bulk).
Skinner, G. William papers
- Series IV. 1956-1958, Indonesia
  - West Kalimantan: Photographs and Fieldnotes (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Photographs and film of coin, Circa 1957 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Probably issued by Heshun Gongsi at Montrado, West Kalimantan; words on coin written out on slip of paper
    - Photographs of Lo Fangbo grave and inscriptions, Mandor (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Photographs given to Skinner by someone called Li Kezhao, probably the person featured in the picture.
    - Photographs of Lanfang Gongsi outpost (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Photographs of Fong Pak Public School, Mandor (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Curator's note, after the Mandor Chinese were evicted from the area in 1967, the school building has fallen into disuse and is now in ruins. These may be the few pictures of the school when it was still intact.
    - Loose notes (Mandor and Lanfang Gongsi), Circa 1957 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Fieldnotes (Montrado), Circa 1957 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Curator's note with notes on Chinese temple in Montrado, now no longer found.
    - Fieldnotes (Singkawang), Circa 1957 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Interviews with Lim Lieh Ngan; Lim Tet San
    - Notes (Catholicism & Demographics), circa 1957 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Interview notes (Mendjalin and Mandor), Circa 1957-12-13 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Features Liu Kezhao, whose name was found among the photos on Mandor; also details on Fong Pak Public School
    - Surat Perdjandjian-Sewa, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Probably collected in 1957.
    - Fieldnotes I (Tour of West Kalimantan), 1957-12-(5-10) (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Seems to be notes written from tour of West Kalimantan; 35 pp.
    - Fieldnotes II (Schools and Temples), Circa 1957 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Focused on schools, temples, organization.
    - Fieldnotes III (Rice Farming), Circa 1957 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Rice farming
    - Fieldnotes IV (Family and Kinship), Circa 1957 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Notes on Dayak-Chinese intermarriage
  - West Kalimantan - Demographic data and Map (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Demographic data, Circa 1957 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Map (West Kalimantan) (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Java, Madura, Bali: Translations and Reading Notes (History) (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Chinese population of Java, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 20)
      Loose notes drawn from a Dutch source
    - "Chinese Influence in Java", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 20)
      By Liem Thian Joe in Jade, no. 2, Year XII, pp. 7-15; notes (4 pp.); from Donald E. Willmott (DEW).
    - The Chinaman Abroad, 1849 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      By Ong Tai Hae; notes (6 pp.) from DEW.
    - Riwajat Semarang, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      By Liem Thian Joe; translated from Indonesia; mainly list of contents (7 pp.) from DEW.
    - "Java, geographisch, ethnologisch, historisch", 1907 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      By P.J. Veth, Vol. IV (Ethnology); translated from Dutch; 10 pp.
    - Perkawinan Indonesia-Tionghoa, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      By Ong Hok Ham; in Indonesian; Star Weekly (15-2-1958; 4 pp.
    - History Reports, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      History reports of Chinese in tanggerang area, Chinese temple in Kebumen and Bagan Siapi-api; drawn from media reports in Indonesia; 3 pp.
    - List of Chinese officials appointed by Dutch, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 20)
      4 pp.
    - Notes on the anti-Chinese character of Sarikat Islam, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 20)
      From a manuscript by Noer prepared for George McT. Kahin
    - "The Past of Overseas Chinese in Java and the Problem of Improving their Future Position", 3/16/1928 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      By Huang Fei-jan, Nan Yang Yan Jiu, Vol 1, No. 4, pp. 53-56, March 16, 1928; translated from Chinese; 3 pp.
    - "An analysis of the characteristics of temples built by the Chinese in Djakarta", 8/13/1956 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      Translation of article in Chung Hua Shang Pao dated 12 May 1954 by Ch’ien Li; original article attached; 6 pp.
    - "Religious and Clan Groups in the Chinese Community in Java", 8/9/1956 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      Translation of series of articles by Ch’ien Li in Chung Hua Shang Pao (Chinese Commercial Press, Djakarta) starting 11 Aug - 8 Sep, 1954; 10 pp.; original articles attached.
    - "Captain Lien Fu-Kuang, Chinese leader during the Hung Ch’i tragedy", 12/17/1956 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      Translation of series of articles by Ch’ien Li in Chung Hua Shang Pao (Chinese Commercial Press, Djakarta) starting 24 nov 1954 and ending Jan 1955; 24 pp.; original articles attached.
    - "A short history of the office of Chinese Affairs - Magistrates Court and its Officials in Batavia, Indonesia", 8/10/1956 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      Translation of article in the Chung Hua Shang Pao, published 23 Feb 1955 and 2 Mar 1955, by K’o Kuan; 8 pp.; original articles attached.
    - "A Brief History of Jakarta Chinese Cemeteries", 1954-9-22; 1954-10-13; 1954-10-20 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      Chinese article in Chung hua Shang Pao by Ch’ien Li; 3 installments.
    - Chronological history of Batavia written by a Chinese, 1840 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      From Periodical Magazine for the Netherlands Indies, 3rd volume, 1840, 2nd part, pp. 1-113; 54 pp.
    - Loose notes in elucidation of The Chronological History of Batavia written by a Chinese, 1840 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      From Periodical Magazine for the Netherlands Indies, 3rd volume, 1840, 2nd part, pp. 114-145; 19 pp.
    - "Oud Batavia", Vol. I, Chp XI, "Foreign Orientals", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 20)
      By Dr de Haan, pp. 485-511 (the Chinese from p. 489); translated from Dutch; 11pp.
    - Geographical and Statistical dictionary of Netherlands-India, 1869 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      From article on Java, Vol. I, pp. 610-640; translated from Dutch; 19 pp.
    - "De ontsluiting van Java’s binnenlanden voor het Wereldverkser", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 20)
      By Dionijs Huibert Burger; 5 pp.
  - GWS Fieldnotes books (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Fieldnotes Book: Java, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Fieldnotes Book: Tjeribon, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Fieldnotes Book: Bali & Java, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Kinship analysis notes (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 22)
      Analysis and comparison of kinship structure among different Indonesian and Chinese ethnic groups.
    - Bahasa dan Budaya:Madjalah Ilmiah Populer, 1956 December (Box 5, Folder 22)
      Indonesian journal; Dec 1956, No. 2, Year 5.
    - "A glance in the Javanese people’s life", 1897 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      By L. Th. Mayer; translation from Dutch; 4 pp.
  - Kinship Terminology data, Notes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Kinship terminology in Indonesian and Chinese languages.
  - Batavia Kong Koan fieldnotes and materials, 6/8/1933 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Reglement Chineesche Raad te Batavia, 6/8/1933 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      Booklet in Dutch.
    - Kong Koan inscriptions, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 24)
      Hand-copied in Chinese.
  - Jakarta Telephone Directory Analysis, Loose notes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 25)
    Ethnic breakdown of telephone directory names in Jakarta
  - GWS Fieldnotes: Djakarta (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Interview: Sanusi, 2/12/1957 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      Head, Djawatan Perindustrian; 2 pp.
    - Ch’ingming, 4/5/1957 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      8 pp. (7 printed, 1 handwritten)
    - Interview: Auwjong Peng Koen, 7/19/1957 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Interview: Injo Beng Goat, 7/19/1957 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      Editor, Keng Po
    - Correspondence: Tan Gin Han, 9/17-24/1956 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Loose notes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 26)
      Interview with Oei Tjoe Tah
  - Surabaya History - Reading and Fieldnotes (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Kinship Charts, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 27)
      Includes Tjoa, Han, Kwee family trees
    - Notes, 8/2/1957 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - "Riwajatnja Familie Tjoa di Soerabaja", 1934 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      By The Boen Liang, in the Extra nummer of "Mata Hari" - Semarang the 1st of Aug, 1934; translation from Malay; 16 pp.
    - Family tree of the Tjoa’s, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 27)
      6 pp.; explanation of family customs
    - Interview - Nitiadiningrat, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 27)
      Former regent of Surabaya; 3 pp.
    - "Probolinggo, geschiedenis en overlevering", 1931 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      By Dr. J.G.W. Lekkerkerker, published by J.H. de Bussy - Amsterdam -1931; translated from Dutch; 4 pp.
    - Almarhoem Tan Boen Liang, 1/22/1930 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      Tan Boen Liang funeral book
    - Huishoudelijk Reglement van het liefdadigheidsfonds Hok Kian Kong Tik Soe afdeeling Hok An Kiong, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - "Oud Soerabaia" by G.H. von Faber, n.d (Box 5, Folder 27)
      Extracted notes translated from Dutch
  - GWS Fieldnotes: Java & Bali (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Jogjakarta Fieldnotes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 28)
      Mostly handwritten, in pencil
    - "The Chinese in Purwokerto", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Purwokerto Fieldnotes, 9/7/1956 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      8 pp.
    - Purwokerto Fieldnotes, 9/9/1956 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      2 pp.
    - Purwokerto Loose notes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 28)
      6 pp.
    - Semarang Interview notes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 28)
      Ko Tjay Sing & Ko Swan Sik; 3 pp.
    - Solo Fieldnotes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Madura Fieldnotes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Bali Fieldnotes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Sukabumi fieldnotes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 28)
      Handwritten, pencil; 3 pp.
    - Bandung fieldnotes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 28)
      Handwritten, pencil; 4 pp.
    - Interview notes, 2/17-18/1957 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      Handwritten, pencil; includes interviews with Moh Rasid, Tan Hwat Tiang, Tan Fay Tjhion, Dr. Sim; 11 pp.
    - Fieldnotes (General), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 28)
      Includes notes on Semarang, Surabaya; 3 pp.
    - Loose notes, 7/18/1956 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      Political party information, probably from Herb Feith; 2 pp.
  - Sukabumi Cross-tabulations, Loose printouts, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 29)
    Only cross-tab printouts
  - Purwokerto Project (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Report outline, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 30)
      In Indonesian; 3 pp.
    - Purwokerto Report, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 30)
      In Indonesian; 58 pp.
    - Receipts, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Wongso correspondence, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Loose notes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 30)
      Thumbnails of various projects
  - Purwokerto Fieldnotes (Wongso) I (Box 5, Folder 31)
    In Indonesian
    - Wongsokenongo fieldnotes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Fieldnotes, 9/9/1956-12/28/1956 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      In Indonesian; pp. 1-119
  - Purwokerto Fieldnotes (Wongso) II, Fieldnotes, 12/29/1956-3/10/1957 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    In Indonesian; pp. 120-250
  - Purwokerto Fieldnotes (Wongso) III, Fieldnotes, 3/12/1957 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    In Indonesian; pp. 251-356
  - Purwokerto Fieldnotes (Wongso) IV, Fieldnotes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 34)
    In Indonesian; pp. 357-508
  - Lecture Notes: Java (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Priyayi, n.d (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Handwritten notes
    - Peasantry, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Abangan, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Chart on Geertz’s priyayi, santri, abangan prototypes, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Java family and kinship, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Santri, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Java: Intro Lecture, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Tables from "A Cross-Cultural Study of Divorce with Special Reference to a Javanese Village in Jogjakarta, Indonesia, Sep-64 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      By Pandam Guritno Siswoharsojo, Master’s thesis, Cornell University
  - MIT Bibliography, Bibliography on the Economic and Political Development of Indonesia, Aug-53 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Compiled by Hedwig Schleiffer, edited by Douglas S. Paauw; Center for International Studies, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Project on the Economic and Political Development of Indonesia; includes only Sections I, V and VI.
  - Bibliographies (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Recent English-Language Publications on Contemporary Indonesia - mainly political, 1963 - March 1964, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Cowa Bibliography: Current Publications in Old World Archaeology (Area 20 - Indonesia), 1957 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Cowa Survey: Current Work in Old world Archaeology (Area 20 - Indonesia), 1957 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Course Outline for Far Eastern Studies 601 (Fall 1954-1955), 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Course Outline for Far Eastern Studies 602: Southeast Asia (Spring 1955), 1955 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Course Outline for FES 602 - Southeast Asia (Indonesia) Spring Term 1957, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Course Outline for FES 975 - Art and Society in Modern Indonesia (Fall 1957-58, 10/1/1957 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Course by Mrs. Claire Holt; 4 pp.
    - Loose reference from A. Hudson, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 3)
      1 p.
    - A Brief Guide to the Indonesian Collection, 1955 September (Box 6, Folder 3)
      14 pp.
    - International Bibliography of Sociology (Indonesia), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 3)
      handwritten
  - Press File: Codings, Abbreviations (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Djarkata Press Clipping File on the Chinese in Indonesia Jan 1956 - Jan 1958 (Coding Key), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Key to Abbreviations, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Write-up Subjects Notes, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Notes, instructions, memo.
    - Earlier versions, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Earlier versions of some of the other contents
    - Loose notes, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Notes on place names
  - Press File Index: A-G (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Index of press clippings according to subject
  - Press File Index: H-L (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Press File Index: M-U (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Bibliographic Notes (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Loose notes on references
  - Bibliographies and Annotations (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Authored books, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Bibliography on Overseas Chinese Culture (Sociology and Anthropology; Java), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Titles in Dutch, Indonesian and Chinese, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Bibliography: Overseas Chinese Cultures (West Borneo), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Annotated Bibliography I, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Annotated Bibliography II, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Press Lists, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Press File: Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - "Culture" and Acculturation (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Chinese New Year or Spring Festival: Origin of Spring Festival, 1956-1958 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Tjapgomeh (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 12)
      1 p.; Dragon boat festival and Hakka songs
    - Chinese gambling (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Peranakan Chinese and Western Culture (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Literature (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Chinese painters in Indonesia (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Drama (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Chinese music and opera (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Chinese acculturation to Indonesian patterns of culture (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Intergroup relations (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - IDr. Ali Akbar’s ideas about the Chinese problems and how to solve them (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Tan Po Goan vs Djody Gondokusumo Case, 11/2/1956 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Han-Harjono incident, 10/17/1956 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      13 pp.
    - Lembaga Persahabatan Indonesia-Tiongkok, 10/23/1956 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Role of the Chinese in Indonesian organizations (except Baperki), and the Indonesian Government, and in Indonesian delegations abroad, 10/20/1956 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Summary of the growth and activities of the Lembaga Persahabatan Indonesia - RRT, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 13)
      Indonesian-Chinese Friendship League (in English); 7 pp.
  - Cultural and Recreational Associations (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Chinese cultural organizations, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - History of Sam Kauw Hui, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Chinese Youth and Sport Organizations, 11/3/1956 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      10 pp.; handwritten.
    - Growth of the Chinese Moslem Union, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Chinese in Parliament (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Anggauta minoritet, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 15)
      1 p; listof minority MPs, 9 of which are of Chinese origin.
    - Problem of the minority seats in parliament and constituent assembly, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 15)
      Probably written by someone named Kwee; 30 pp.
    - Minority Representation in Parliament and Constituent Assembly, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 15)
      124 pp.
  - Relations with China (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Visits of Chinese from Indonesia to RRT, 1/12/1956-12/19/1957 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      17 pp.
    - RRT Diplomats and Officials in Indonesia, 1/6/1956-1/6/1958 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      12 pp.
    - RRT Policy toward Overseas Chinese from and in Indonesia, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 16)
      18 pp.
    - Taiwan Policy toward Overseas Chinese, 2/1/1956-1/3/1958 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Citizenship and Immigration (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Extracts from a Pedoman on the question of Indonesian citizenship, 8/17/1951 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      Compiled by Safioedin; 3 pp.
    - The Citizenship Question, 10/22/1956 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Overzicht van de Nationnalistische beweging in Indonesie - in de jaren 1930 tot 1942, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Comments by Gouw Giok Siong on Willmott’s Interim Report, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Immigration department regulations, 10/9/1958 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Economic discrimination, Government policy in the economic field as it distinguishes between asli-Indonesians, non-asli Indonesians and foreigners, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    By LKG; 44 pp.
  - Assaat Movement (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - The Assaat Movement in Indonesia (Indonesian Press), 10/12/1956 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      By Kwee; based on Indonesian language newspapers; 36 pp.
    - The Assaat Movement in Indonesia (Chinese Press), 1/1/1956-9/31/1956 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      By LKG; supplement based on editorials of Chinese language newspapers, covering 1 Jan -31 Sep 1956; 5 pp.
    - The Assaat Movement in the period Oct 1956 - Jan 1958, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 19)
      By LKG; 103 pp.
  - Business and Trade Associations (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Chinese business and trade associations, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 20)
      List of business and trade associations; 4 pp.
    - Press reports, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 20)
      Press editorials and reports; 5 pp.
  - Chinese-Asli Business Cooperation (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Chinese-Asli Business Cooperation, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - List of Joint Chinese Indonesian Enterprises, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      Includes 11 reports of interviews with such enterprises dated 1957-7-10 to 1957-7-22; 20 pp.
  - Smuggling and corruption cases (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - The Hong Kong Compensation Case and Yang Wei Pin’s and Khouw Kim Eng’s Role in this Smuggling Affair, 10/19/1956 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Hong Kong Barter Case, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Ramifications, including political, of Chinese businessmen as corruptors, 11/30/1958 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      9 pp.
    - The Lie Hok Thay Affair, 10/19/1956 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      11 pp.
  - RM (Research & Materials) - Translation and Reading Notes (Historical) (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Translations and Reading Notes: 1900-1945 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Translations and Reading Notes (Postwar) (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Community and Political Leaders (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Loose notes, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Biographies of Chinese Community Leaders, Circa 1957 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      5 pp.; press write-up by LTT.
    - Life History of Go Tiauw Goan and Dr. Kwa Tjoan Sioe, 11/8/1956 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Translations and reading notes: History of Education (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Excerpts from "De eigen Onderwijsvoorziening der Chineezen", 1939 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      By Nio Joe Lan, in Koloniale Studien, 23, (1939), no. 1, 67-95; translated from Dutch
    - Het onderwijs voor de Chinezen (the education for the Chinese), 1936 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      By Dr R. van Diffelen; in Koloniale Studien XX, no. 5, 6 (1936), pp. 42 -63; translated from Dutch.
    - Iets over het onderwijs van Chineesche kinderen van minvermogende ouders in Indonesie, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      By Lee Ping Kian, in weekly "Sin Po", no. 682-689 (25 Apr 1936 - 13 Juni 1936); translated from Dutch.
    - Het Schoolonderwijs onder den Chineezen op Java (The education at schools among the Chinese of Java, 1879 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      By J.E. Albrecht, in Tijdschrift voor Indische Taal-Land en Volkenkunde, no. 25 (1879), pp. 225-241; translated from Dutch
    - A summary of the national education of the overseas Chinese in the East Indies, 11/30/1956 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      By Le T’ien, translation of Chinese article in "Sin Po Jubileum - Nummer 1910 - 1935"; 14 pp.
    - History of Chung Hwa Hui School, Semarang, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 27)
      Press write-up; by LTT.
    - A Brief History of the Chung Hua Hui Kuan in Djakarta, 8/26/1956 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      By Yang Shih Hsiang, translation from Chinese of article in "Tiong Hoa Hwee Koan Djakarta Fiftieth Anniversary 3 June 1900 - 3 June 1950"; 12 pp.
    - Catholic schools for Chinese prewar, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Reading notes and materials (education) (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Education of the mission to Chinese, 11/23/1954 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      Translated from Dutch memo written by A.W.M. Wap from Medan; Dutch original included.
    - Chinese and higher education, 10/19/1956 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      Press write-up
    - Chinese schools and the Indonesian language, 8/20/1956 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      Translated from Chinese article by Shao Chin Piao in "Tiong Hoa Hwee Koan Djakarta Fiftieth Anniversary 3 June 1900 - 3 June 1950"; 4 pp.
    - Chinese culture and the education of overseas Chinese, 8/21/1956 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      Translated from Chinese article by Hsieh Tso Yu in "Tiong Hoa Hwee Koan Djakarta Fiftieth Anniversary 3 June 1900 - 3 June 1950"; 5 pp.
  - GWS Notes - Education (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Loose notes, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Cities and towns with over 500 students in Chinese schools, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - School reports, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 29)
      Reports of schools included in 1957 survey
  - Statistics - Chinese schools and students (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Chinese schools statistics I, Circa 1957 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Chinese schools statistics II, Circa 1957 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Chinese schools statistics (whole Indonesia), Circa 1957 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Chinese schools statistics (West Kalimantan), Circa 1957 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Chinese schools statistics chart, Circa 1957 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Non-Chinese schools statistics, Circa 1957 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Chinese population chart (1930), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Loose notes, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 30)
      Preparatory notes for the statistics charts
  - Ministry of Education Materials (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Statistik Inspeksi Pengadjaran Asing, 4/30/1955 (Box 6, Folder 31)
      23 pp.
    - List of foreign schools in Java, 9/1/1954 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Ministry instructions I, 11/13/1957 (Box 6, Folder 31)
      From the Ministry of Education; Indonesian.
    - Ministry instructions II, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 31)
      Concerning military power and foreign education; Indonesian.
    - Ministry instructions III, 8/13/1957 (Box 6, Folder 31)
      From the Foreign Education Bureau; Indonesian.
    - Report I (Box 6, Folder 31)
      From Roundtable Conference 2 November 1949; Indonesian.
    - Report II, 1958, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 31)
      On supervision of foreign education; Indonesian.
    - Report III, 10/7/1957 (Box 6, Folder 31)
      Summary of Skinner’s book "Chinese Society in Thailand"; Indonesian.
  - Glover - Chinese in Indonesia 1947-1949, Reactions of the Indonesian Chinese to Two Years of Dutch-Indonesian Conflict, 1/10/1950 (Box 6, Folder 32)